Maude Adams Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Maude Adams Papers 1925-1956
MSS10215
Adams, Maude, 1872-1953
19 items 2 containers 0.6 linear feet
Manuscript Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
American stage actress, writer, educator. Annotated typescripts and mimeographed copies of Adams's unpublished autobiography, writings relating to the study of acting, a commencement address, notes for a proposed radio program, a religious play, and the corrected typescript of Phyllis Robbins's biography, Maude Adams, An Intimate Portrait.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
People
Adams, Maude, 1872-1953.; Robbins, Phyllis. Maude Adams; an intimate portrait. 1956.
Subjects
Acting.; Actresses--Biography.; Radio programs.
Occupations
Actresses.; Authors.; Educators.
Administrative Information
Provenance
The papers of Maude Adams, actress, writer, and educator, were given to the Library of Congress by Phyllis Robbins in 1956 and by the Schlesinger Library, Radcliffe College, Cambridge, Massachusetts, in 1985.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of Maude Adams are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Maude Adams, born in Salt Lake City, Utah, in 1872, was an American stage actress. Active in the years 1888-1916, she was a successful and high-paid performer known mostly for her role as Peter Pan. Adams headed the drama department at Stephens College in Columbia, Missouri, from 1937 to 1943. She died in Tannersville, New York, in 1953.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Maude Adams (1872-1953) span the years circa 1925-circa 1956. The entire collection is composed of writings by Maude Adams and a draft by Phyllis Robbins of her biography of Adams, Maude Adams: An Intimate Portrait, published in 1956. The writings of Adams include both published and typescript versions of magazine articles, a speech, a religious play, a book-length typescript and a pamphlet for teaching speech, and a proposal with scripts for a radio program with Homer Saint-Gaudens.
Arrangement of the Papers
This collection is arranged by type of material.
http://lccn.loc.gov/mm79010215
Container List
- Writings (Box 1)
  - By Maude Adams (Box 1)
    - Articles (Box 1)
      - "The One I Knew Least of All" (Box 1)
        - Published copy, Ladies Home Journal, 1926 (Box 1)
        - Typescript, circa 1925, (2 folders) (Box 1)
      - "'Thumbs Up' for Joy and Adventure," typescript and published copy from Ladies Home Journal, 1927, undated (Box 1)
    - Book draft, "The First Steps in Speaking Verse," with an anthology, undated, (3 folders) (Box 1)
    - Commencement address, Stephens College, Columbia, Mo., 1939 (Box 1)
    - Miscellany, undated (Box 1)
    - "Pamphlet on English Speech and English Verse," circa 1947 (Box 1)
    - Play, life of Jesus Christ, undated (Box 1)
    - Radio program proposal, with Homer Saint-Gaudens (Box 1)
      - Description and scripts, undated (Box 1)
      - Notes, undated (Box 1)
  - By Phyllis Robbins, Maude Adams: An Intimate Portrait, typescript, circa 1956, (3 folders) (Box 2)